# Kimberly Hyder-Grogan

## **Medical Office Specialist**

Dallas, TX 75232 kmccullock1@gmail.com (214)355-8915

My objective is to become a team player within a great company where I can utilize my patient care abilities and interpersonal skills in order to provide the highest level of care. To grow professionally so that I might contribute to the growth of the company.

#### Summary of Qualifications:

\*Over 17 years of working in the healthcare field.

\*Highly skilled in the procedures of patient registration, insurance verification. Scheduling of new and established patients. Taking inbound and outbound calls in a call center environment. Abilities to pay close attention to details.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

## Work Experience

## **PBX Operator**

KFORCE FLEXIBLE SOLUTIONS LLC- Texas Health Resorces - Arlington, TX September 2018 to Present

Handling a commercial telephone switching system. My job entails basic customer service. Answering all incoming calls to the hospital and direct those calls, route these incoming calls to the correct individual or department within the hospital or send to a message system, such as voicemail, if required. Overhead paging of Codes (Code Blue, Code Pink, Rapid Response, etc....)

#### **Pre-Registration Representative ER Department**

AppleOne - Fort Worth, TX

November 2017 to November 2017

Welcoming patients and family members in a professional manner.

Interview patients at work station or at bedside to obtain all necessary account information.

Utilizing carts with computers, scanners and

printers on wheels

Ensure charts are completed and accurate.

Verifying all insurance and obtaining pre- certifications and authorizations.

Calculating and collecting patients liable amounts.

#### **Medical Screener/Receptionist**

CSL Plasma - Dallas, TX

October 2017 to November 2017

Greeting donors at the plasma collection center

Conducting a series of registration procedures

to verify donor suitability for the plasma pheresis process Assisting qualified donors in completing the screening process. Educating new donors of policies and procedures. Maintaining confidentiality at all times.

## **Physician Office Representative**

Jobnet America- Baylor Family Medical - Waxahachie, TX November 2016 to May 2017

Answering all incoming calls that came into the office for three locations Scheduling and rescheduling appointments and procedures for each doctor. Taking messages and routing calls to the correct department, physician and nursing staff. Insurance verification.

Use of Centricity and EPIC

## **Patient Access Representative**

USMD Internal Medicine - Arlington, TX January 2015 to August 2016

Answering of all incoming calls and making outgoing calls: call center environment Scheduling and re-scheduling of appointments

Making calls confirming appointments

Answering up to 100 calls per day

Routing calls accordingly and taking messages for up to 14 doctors and nurses.

Scanning all documents into patients charts

The use of EMR, Electronic Medical Records System and EHR, Electronic Health System.

## **Patient Registration Representative**

Medsynergies - Irving, TX October 2012 to September 2013

Register Patient Demographics into Centricity System; Flowcast & Groupcast Insurance Verification via Web, Phone System

## **Medical Billing Specialist**

Pinnacle Consultants LP - Dallas, TX January 2011 to February 2012

Dallas, TX

Knowledge of CPT, ICD-9, ASA and HCPCS coding

Knowledge of Medicare, Medicaid and Workers Compensation rules and regulations

Skill in keyboarding/data entry

Skill in computer applications including MS Word, MS Excel

Skill in verbal and written communication

Review anesthesia records for supporting documentation for charge tickets

Enter charge data on each patient into the patient accounting system with high level of accuracy.

Expected performance is to enter 145+ charge tickets.

Review Batch Error reports for errors/rejections and make necessary corrections

Assist the Collection Department with corrections and billing issues as needed

Run daily concurrency reports and audit for compliance

## **Account Information Specialist**

Pinnacle Consultants LP - Dallas, TX November 2008 to January 2011

Register Patient Demographics into IDX System Insurance Verification via Web, Phone System, Fax Data-Entry Maintain daily logs and daily average of 150 to 200 tickets

Request face sheets or other information as required
Review all documents upon receipt to ensure all information is attached
General knowledge of Government Payers, Commercial, Workers Compensation

Training new hires on policies and procedures and fundamentals of job duties.

## **Patient Registration/Insurance Verification Specialist**

Medical Edge - Dallas, TX September 2007 to May 2008

Registering Patients Demographics into IDX System Data-Entry Insurance Verification via Web, Phone System, Fax

#### **HIM Specialist**

Parkland Hospital - Dallas, TX July 2001 to July 2005

Enter patient information into hospital database Maintain hospital files using both alpha/numeric filing Front desk duties (answering multi-line phone system) Chart location and retrieval in timely manner Release Of Information

#### Education

#### **Certificate in Medical Business Office Specialist**

Allied Career Center - Dallas-Fort Worth, TX 2007

#### **GED**

Home Study Careers - Dallas, TX 1999 to 1999

#### Skills

Profound ability to maintain confidentiality in all aspects of the job; Good analytical skills with high accurateness; Good organizational skills; Excellent customer relation skills. Skilled in the use of EMR and EPIC., Customer Service, data entry, scheduling

## Additional Information

Professional References: Shanese Parker 469-383-4879 Laura Landin 817-881-8860 Alton Drayden 972-217-0487